i'm starting off today's episode by
running the extremely loud and annoying
zero tick sugarcane farm that's because
i'm stocking up i'm stocking up big time
i've hit a few realizations today
and it's not good it's not good on
several fronts
i have been working and tinkering away
with the base i have lowered this a
couple of blocks and i've been wondering
what i'm actually going to do with the
inside and i've come to several
conclusions one
this area up here will not be big enough
for an enormous item sorter
so
i'm gonna have to move it underground
realization number two underground
doesn't exist i've got to mine it all
out and then realization number three is
if i want to use this space as an
underground area for my item sorter i'm
gonna have to get rid of this now i'm
gonna have to get rid of this anyway
because 1.16 update will make this
obsolete and not work
but i'm probably gonna have to get rid
of it before then
so
welcome to hermitcraft
lots of realizations
lots of oh i didn't think this through
in today's episode however
it is good news that i have got a steady
plan for what we're going to do now
today i hope to work a little bit more
on this section being repeated over here
and getting some more details in
and i really hope to get something
really impressive going on here i
accidentally made something that works
super well this staircase goes up really
far but actually when you're walking
through here this long corridor i think
this looks really really impressive so i
reckon if this gets extended and this
gets mined out this could end up looking
pretty impressive so we'll leave this
running for a little bit
and we'll just fill up an enormous
amount of double chests full of
sugarcane it's going to take a while but
it's got to be done gotta stock up for
the rest of the season the rest of the
season people
and i also noticed
the game of naughts and crosses
continues i've actually got rid of the
bell that was here because it was
actually driving me mad
boom let's have a look
i think like i said i think this is
going to end up in a tie yeah this is uh
this is going to be a tie look here well
you know what actually i'm
i'll let him take the win shall i but
everyone you have to pretend like he you
have to pretend like he did this all by
himself what a clever mumbo what a
clever mumbo oh look at me oh look at me
i'm green i'm going for the win look at
that but next there put this in
enjoy your win mumbo
i hope it brings you happiness
whoa whoa
whoa
hi
hi why aren't you wearing any feet feet
feet
why aren't you wearing any socks
where's your armor
i can see i can see his pink slippers uh
hi how can i help you how can i help you
mr pink slippers hmm
i have prizes and stuff for what
i totally forgot about the head hunt oh
my goodness all right i'm gonna call
scar hi
um
i have a confession go on well i came
over here to give you the prize but it's
not in my under chest and i don't know
where it's at are you telling me that we
won
is that is that what happened yeah but
the worst part of it is that i don't
know what the diamonds happened where
did they go so they lost
so we we won but you've lost my half of
the prize pool well you could help me go
look in some of my chests for them have
you got a chest monster
no come on how many points did we win by
i didn't i didn't actually get to see
the ceremony of who won i have no idea
i heard that we won and that's all it
counted
cool i don't think the diamonds is all
that you've lost cause i think you know
i can see your pink slippers i did i
lost the diamonds but i did i did get
you this one large armor stand scene
oh is this from cleo
yeah that is awesome
yeah but the diamonds i'm putting i'm
putting in that but you know
i'm not gonna let this this diamond
thing slide so you're gonna have to
locate those diamonds for me
i'm gonna find them like i could use
some help if you if you don't mind fine
oh my are you serious
dude i've also got a massive chest
monster growing as well like i started
off being really organized and then it
just descended into this i i i you know
it's just going to take a little bit of
time here to find them
uh i lost i lost everything what have
you done
i found him he found the dive found them
up here up here found them i'm coming
come in here
um yeah yeah right here right here 32
yeah boom
blocks of diamonds oh man that feels
good okay well uh good luck with your um
problems
and
also high five for the diamonds right
high five oh did you see that high five
that was like a chess bomb here let's do
it again i mean that's pretty nice oh no
what's happened uh
either lag broke this machine
or because i unloaded the chunks it
didn't work okay
hold on let's see if we can fix this it
should be as simple as just placing
these back in
oh no
oh this is really bad
stop
stop this is an actual nightmare you
know what this might be
this might be one of those times where i
just fix it later
ah
it's just
every time i fix it it just breaks
itself and i can't i can't cope with
this today i can't cope with this
oh i totally took i was meant to only
take 16 diamonds blocks whoops uh is oh
scar's gone offline now hmm i'm gonna
give these back but you know what i'm
gonna
i'm gonna make a little uh little beard
for larry here now i've only got 16
blocks so i've kind of got to
move them sparingly i don't want i don't
want scar to think i just like i just
nabbed all of his profit because he
worked he worked hard on this and we
worked i think we worked really well as
a team there we go
larry the snail is now wearing
a bling beard
i think that has actually made me far
more wealthy than i was before 16 on six
22 blocks of diamond not a bad place to
start i'm really glad that we won the
head hunt it was a lot of fun
but now it's time to work on the other
game that's going on the server yeah
there is another game we actually
started it remember remember tag two
electric boogaloo now that that's going
oh
what is this
do not touch this until these signs are
gone
do
cheers mumbo is it just a box with a
button is there something up there i
don't understand
i don't understand the thing
why are there lots of redstone lamps
anyway as i was saying we're gonna go
over to the shopping district what a
weird machine it's actually been a while
since i've been in the shopping district
i haven't had a good look around oh my
goodness it's starting to transform
quite a lot and i've still just got my
tiny little barge going on over there
don't worry we'll do something about
this and look at the size of the diamond
pile we have to do something about that
too but look at this
this is a tag two electric boogaloo it's
looking
very sad so i'm thinking what we need to
do is since tag two electric boogaloo
kind of got put to the wayside while the
head game was going on i just let it go
you know just just let it tick on in the
background but now now that the head
game is done it's time to ramp things up
we need to make this
uh more inviting to play now since lots
of people have already signed up i don't
know people can still sign up if they
want to but since that's all done
i think we should make
something a little bit more tasteful
for this and show how many diamonds are
actually up for grabs
so we'll take one of our brand new
diamonds we'll pop it here on the pile
and we'll make ourselves a nice little
area for tag two electric boogaloo let's
go uh it's certainly not its older
brother which is the enormous pile of
diamonds it's it's slightly younger
brother um the tag two electric boogaloo
prize pool now obviously this looks a
little bit
well
it's not a lot let's put it that way and
that's probably why the hermits aren't
as interested in the tag
as they should be so to kind of combat
this i'm going to add my own diamonds to
the pool and some also some incentive
boxes there's a full shulker box full of
golden carrots always worth it
a full shulker box full of gravel and a
full shulker box full of sand and this
is just to kick it off just to ramp
things up a little bit so the prize pool
will grow and grow and grow as i get
more and more stuff
and hopefully people will get more and
more invested in collecting the tag
actually i have no idea who actually has
the tag
does anybody know does anybody know who
has the tag
so these are all the people that are
currently playing and you can still sign
up if you want to add to the prize pool
okay so that's looking a little bit
better again there's no point in making
this look absolutely phenomenal
fantastic just because well the game
will end i'll have to take it all back
down again so this is just a better way
of visually showing what's on offer
now the next question what do we do
about the hms
ggg green great green goodies well i
actually have a plan now i have a plan
and i'm gonna have to claim all of this
water before it all goes i'm gonna i'm
gonna use all this up but my plans keep
changing but i've finally settled
settled on an idea and i'm gonna go for
it so let's quickly expand this
as much as possible and that means we're
also gonna have to invest these diamonds
that i've been saving up i got 13
diamond blocks one two three four five
six seven eight
nine ten eleven twelve all right we'll
put 12 of these onto the enormous pile
of diamonds
to cover our place
boom and then we have now claimed all of
this water so let's quickly expand this
[Music]
at some point it stops becoming a barge
and more like an enormous wooden
platform and i think we've reached that
point some of you might be thinking this
looks pretty cool a lot of you will be
thinking wow this looks really ugly and
i am inclined to agree agree with you
slightly it's not the best looking thing
in the world but remember this is an
investment project the more we sell the
more we invest in it and it's actually
about the size that i want it to be so
if we get some more sales on these
platforms we can upgrade this further
and i'm thinking a full-on structure on
top of the wooden platform is due next
but for that we're gonna need more stock
we're gonna need some more diamonds whoa
i left this just overnight and it's
already sold loads well the investment
continues people oh my goodness this
thing moves faster than i can uh then i
can deal with so i've added a couple of
things here i've added some more golden
carrots in its own platform and i've
added name tags and you get one diamond
four now they sound quite expensive
that's because they are they are 15
emeralds each so one diamond for a name
tag is not a bad deal actually and then
i've set up a bunch of platforms for
future stock now there's no point
upgrading this platform until all of
these things are stocked up so i need to
decide what am i going to sell look i
say more stock soon more stock coming
soon i have more stock soon i said soon
okay there's no stock here seriously
so hopefully we'll get some more sales
and we'll be able to upgrade this even
further but before we depart i actually
want to give this uh a little bit of
greenery in here because it's uh looking
i don't know it looks a bit i have no
dead around it so we'll add some sea
grass under the platform there we go
that already looks a lot better just
with some sea grass in it absolutely
perfect now i bet a lot of you won't
even guess where this is going next but
my priority now is to get this stock
installed
and now we can head back
to the base
i've been tinkering with a few things
off camera and i think i know what i
want to do next so one thing that i've
done is actually started having a little
go with this corridor and i think i sort
of nailed what i want to do i i
essentially want an extremely long
corridor with some really nice pillars
and some nice rounded tops and i also
spent a long time fixing this thing
which
was an absolute nightmare but looks like
it's all good now i hope
so i have prepared a lot of blocks for
what we're going to need the terracotta
uh the concrete powder and all of the
stoney type stuff that we're going to
need now i think we should just go for
it all right
let's go
[Music]
every time i sit down to do a time lapse
on this build i think yeah this time i'm
gonna get loads done well four and a
half hours later and all we really got
done was a mirror of the other side i
have added this little bit of detail on
the front which i think is good but i
haven't quite sussed out how to detail
some of the other bits now you might
have noticed right at the end of the
time lapse that i've started carving
away at this that's because i have
figured out what i'm going to put here
so that might be what i do next but i am
just hacking away slowly at this build
bit by bit it is getting steadily and
steadily bigger and bigger and oh
smaller and smaller in some cases once
again i find myself short of certain
resources dark prismarine for example so
i'm gonna head over to the shopping
district to grab some more oh oh
oh
i was just passing through the signs are
gone the signs are gone what does the
button do it just it just puts the
lights back on
oh
uh purple concrete cool
you know maybe i should have read the
book before i press the button
i'ma read the book the button what is it
the button is alive and has to be kept
alive by being pressed basically i'm a
hero i've saved the button the closer to
death the button is when you save it the
higher rank you get signified by a
colored belt put on your skin how does
it work if you press the button the
redstone lamps will fill back up and
you'll get a colored piece of concrete
this is your rank and then you should
attach the rank to your skin should you
laugh at people who are a lower rank
than you yes 100
yes there is no gray belt that is not a
rank uh
it's all fun and games but people with
purple belts should be ridiculed
long live the button oh no oh no this is
why you read the book first
before you press the button uh no i
can't even i can't even be rumbled
i can't even act like i didn't just did
this
oh no
i better go and see what this purple
belt thing is all about oh look it's on
my hand look at my hand maybe maybe for
me first but look i'm gonna wear this
with pride you don't have to make fun of
me just because i got the purple belt i
call this purple power if you ask me i'm
gonna add this in here purple belts
welcome here
[Laughter]
right we actually came here for some
dark prismary before we got distracted
by a wild button i mean that's how you
get me isn't it just put a button
somewhere i'll press it that's how it
works i'll just press it
i'm getting really close
real close
wowie okay right let's uh i actually
need a tiny bit more
one two three and back we go
okay so now that we've actually made a
bit of progress here i want to start
doing some work
underneath here now you can see that i
started i actually want to do a little
bit more to make this look a bit nicer
so i'm going to need to get myself a few
blocks
whoa
what is this
hi thank you for getting my stuff back
here is a gift for dragon wings from the
tri wizard tournament first task oh my
goodness okay so again
this is something that happened off
camera but scar died and cub and i went
searching for his stuff and we found it
and he's given me a bunch of stuff
thanks ska that's real kind of you
i'm going to need these it's oh look at
that chinese fireball welsh green dragon
oh he's named them all after harry
potter dragons why was i here oh so i
was thinking i need to decorate these
and i want it to look really really
fancy and elegant
and one thing you can do to all of your
pillars to make them look that little
bit nicer is at the bottom just add some
trapdoors
and it gives it that little extra bit of
foundation beneath it and then what i'm
gonna do here
is try and create a nice archway i want
to try and create some really nice
detailing with it if i can and then to
get some of those finer angles i can use
some trapdoors oh my goodness oh my
goodness there's an army after me all
right i'm bailing out of this one
okay i have a bit of an issue with the
amount of mobs that are here i think
that looks pretty good the issue here
though is the stone in the ceiling so
i'll have to think of something for that
but on the whole i think this is turning
out to be quite a nice little entrance
that we've got going on here i need to
choose a nice floor block and then i've
got the daunting task of actually
excavating the whole of the inside i
think this has been a pretty good
episode in terms of base building but
i'm gonna have to tinker away with this
off camera a little bit to try and work
out what i want to do here
now before we end this episode i
actually want to go back to the button
machine because i've got the purple belt
right here and i'm i'm quite happy
um but i would really like to collect
all of them
all of the belts
oh
boop
green
i think there's people waiting
[Laughter]
i'm happy with that
what's going on
what's going
going on
okay so i need the blue the yellow the
orange and then finally the red is there
a problem
i saw the opportunity and i took it
i think doc's i i think doc was maybe
waiting for a better belt and i've just
i've come in and come in and swooped it
he's like looking off into the distance
like what have i become
this button game
i love it it's so stupid
all right so now i got the green one too
mumbo what have you done i don't know if
i really want to i mean good luck good
luck waiting for that to be red because
i think as soon as it becomes any color
i'm just going to press it
i'm just going to press it well i
actually think that i want to try and
collect them all instead of changing out
i think i'll be a lot of fun and who
knows maybe if i collect them all
i might be able to